nursinglink.com 2008-10-04

# Privacy - Nursing Link

### Overview

NursingLink is committed to respecting the privacy of our users. We strive to provide a safe, secure user experience. NursingLink is a property of Monster Worldwide. This Privacy Statement sets forth the online data collection and usage policies and practices that apply to the NursingLink , Monster and Affinity Communities Sites (including, but not limited to, InsideTech, NursingLink, TechCommunity, The Apple, GovCentral, and FireLink) (sometimes collectively referred to herein as the "Monster Sites" or “Affinity Communities”) and does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. Your data will be stored and processed in the United States. The information we gather on the Monster Sites may be shared within the Monster-affiliated companies on a worldwide basis in order to deliver the products and services we offer to employers such as searches for job seekers or in order to undertake analysis of our database such as aggregate profiling of our registered users, or in order to connect job seekers with communities of like-minded professionals as well as vocation, profession, or interest-focused resources. "Affiliated companies" means entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with Monster, Inc. The Monster Sites contain links to other Web sites over which we have no control. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other Web sites to which you choose to link from our Sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other Web sites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information.

### Collection and Use of Information by Monster

In some areas of the Monster Sites we may request that you provide personal information, including your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number, social security number, contact information, billing information and any other information from which your identity is discernible. In other areas, we collect or may collect demographic information that is not unique to you such as your ZIP code, age, preferences, gender, interests and favorites. Sometimes we collect or may collect a combination of the two types of information. Examples of areas on the Monster Sites where we collect personal or combined personal and demographic data are pages where you can open an Affinity Community account, create a Monster Networking profile or account, sign up to use a service, post a resume or profile, enter a contest or purchase a product. We also gather or may gather certain information about your use of the Monster Sites such as what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that is or may be collected by us. This information can include without limitation your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses, but is not linked to your personal information. We may sometimes afford you the opportunity to provide descriptive, cultural, behavioral, preferential and/or life style information about yourself, but it is solely up to you whether you furnish such information. If you do provide such information, you are thereby consenting to the use of that information in accordance with the policies and practices described in this Privacy Statement. For example, such information may be used for the purpose of determining your potential interest in receiving e-mail or other communications about particular products or services. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about the Monster Sites or refer a job posting to a friend, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Monster Sites or view the job posting. We do not store this information.

### Our Use of Your Information

We use the information we gather on the Monster Sites whether personal, demographic, collective or technical, for the purpose of operating and improving the Monster Sites, fostering a positive user experience, and delivering the products and services that we offer. If you have provided consent for us to do so, we may also use the information we gather to inform you of other products or services available from us or our affiliated companies. We may use your contact information in order to send you e-mail or other communications regarding updates at the Monster Sites, to contact you about your opinion of current products and services or potential new products and services that may be offered. We may also provide additional communications, promotions and information on new Monster opportunities and additional job postings which may be of interest to you. The nature and frequency of these messages will vary depending upon the information we have about you. In addition, you may receive free informational newsletters from us relating to topics that may be of special interest to you, such as career management advice. We have areas on the Monster Sites where you can submit feedback. Any feedback you submit in these areas becomes our property, and we can use such feedback (such as success stories) for marketing purposes or to contact you for further information.

### Choices Regarding the Disclosure of Personal Information to Others 

We do not disclose your personal information to third parties, or your combined personal and demographic information or information about your use of Monster Sites or NursingLink (such as the areas you visit or the services you access), except as set forth below. 1\. We disclose information to third parties if you consent to such disclosure. For example, if you indicate that you would like to receive information about the opportunities, products or services of third parties at the time you register for an NursingLink account, we supply your contact information to third parties such as employers, recruiters, data aggregators, and educational institutions, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you e-mail or otherwise communicating with you. We use data we have about you (such as the interests and preferences you have expressed) to determine whether you might be interested in the opportunities, products or services of a particular third-party. 2\. We disclose information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include hosting our Web servers, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies and individuals will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party. 3\. We disclose information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. 4\. We disclose and transfer information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of our business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event we become the subject of a bankruptcy proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, we or our trustee in bankruptcy may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the bankruptcy court. You will be notified of sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party via email or through a prominent notice posted on the Monster Sites.

### Personal Profiles 

NursingLink is designed for member networking among other like-minded professionals with similar backgrounds and/or interests. If you have a profile on a Monster Site or NursingLink , other users or members of Monster Sites may view your profile. Your personal information, including demographic information, may be made public in your personal profile; however, your contact information is not displayed. Other users or members of Monster Sites will not have access to your contact information unless you choose to share it with them. We are not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of profile information in the instance of other members who have accessed your profile and may have retained information from your profile in their own files or databases.

### Posting to Public Areas of Monster

Please remember that if you post any of your personal information in public areas of Monster, Monster Networking, or NursingLink such as in online forums or chat rooms, or in the Monster searchable resume database, such information may be collected and used by others over whom we have no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of Monster or NursingLink.

### Other Uses of Information

We also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to Monster, Monster Networking or NursingLink (for example, the number of visitors to Monster's Diversity & Inclusion area or Public Service area) with its clients, partners and other third parties so that they can understand the kinds of visitors to the Monster Sites and how those visitors use the Monster Sites. We may also aggregate on an anonymous basis data regarding job qualifications, schooling, age, experience level or other information relevant to the job search or competition among Seekers for any such job. Such data may be made available to employers or fellow job seekers. Information gathered on a page on a co-branded page (such as that of a contest co-sponsored by Monster and another company), may become the property of the other company or of both us and the other company. NursingLink may offer a number of third party services from its Sites, such as ecommerce stores for gear or discussion boards hosted by a service provider. If you choose to use these optional services, we may provide some of your personally identifiable information, including your name, address, and email to the Co-Brand Service Provider offering such services in order for them to provide the service. Conversely, the co-Brand Service Provider may provide NursingLink with personal information about you. In those instances, the use of such information by the other company will be subject to the privacy policy of that company. While we carefully evaluate and choose such companies, we are not responsible for that company's use of your personal or demographic information. If you apply for a job on Monster, Monster Sites or NursingLink, you may be asked to provide information on your gender, race or other protected status where permitted by applicable law. Some employers are required by law to gather this information from job applicants for reporting and record-keeping requirements. You should understand that if provided, this information will be used by employers only in accordance with applicable law and will not be used in making any negative employment decisions. All information provided will be kept separate from your expression of interest in any job opportunity. Providing this information is strictly voluntary and you will not be subject to any adverse action or treatment if you choose not to provide this information.

### Use of Cookies

We use "cookies" to help personalize and maximize your online experience and time online. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard drive by a Web page server. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to your computer, and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Monster pages, or register for services, a cookie helps us to recall your specific information (such as user name, password and preferences). Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster and more accurate results and a more personalized site experience. When you return to Monster, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. We also use cookies to track click streams and for load balancing. You may have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline all cookies if you prefer. Alternatively, you may be able to modify your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. If you choose to decline cookies, however, that may hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on Monster and Monster Networking.

### Use of Web Beacons

Monster and NursingLink Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Web beacons are not used to access your personally identifiable information; they are a technique we use to compile aggregated statistics about our Web site usage. Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides. You may not decline web beacons, however, they can be rendered ineffective by declining all cookies or modifying your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis.

### Access to and Modification of Your Information

You may review, correct, update or change your Monster Networking profile, or NursingLink account or profile information at any time. To change your NursingLink account or profile information, simply log into your account, go to your Account profile, review your account information and, if you wish, edit it with the options provided. Click [here](http://www.nursinglink.com/account%E2%80%9D) to access your NursingLink account page, and [click here](http://www.nursinglink.com/account) to access your NursingLink profile page. If you opted to receive newsletters, commercial e-mails or other communications from NursingLink or third parties at the time you created your account, but have changed your mind, you may opt out by editing your account page as described above. If you previously opted not to receive such communication, you may later opt in by editing your account page as well. We retain indefinitely all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use of Monster or NursingLink more efficient, practical, and relevant. Of course, you can delete your resume from Monster's online database, close your NursingLink account at any time, in which event we will remove all our copies of your resume from Monster and your NursingLink account information, except for an archival copy which is not accessible on the Internet.

### Security of the Personal Information

We have implemented commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. If you choose to make a purchase or when you place an order online at Monster or NursingLink , your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for your credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted..If you make a purchase from a third-party service provider through a Monster Site (such as ecommerce sites for gear), your credit card data, as well as other personal information necessary for the transaction, will be transmitted to the third-party. The data will then be subject to the service provider’s privacy policy and security practices. We can not be held responsible for that company’s use of your information.

### Children

The Monster Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.

### Safe Harbor

We participate in the Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Framework arising out of the U.S. implementation of the European Union Data Protection Directive. We have certified adherence to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles for the Monster and Monster Networking Sites. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Web site. If you would like to contact us directly about the Safe Harbor program, please send an e-mail to safeharbor@monster.com.

### Changes to Privacy Statement

If we decide to materially change our Privacy Statement for Monster and NursingLink we will post those changes through a prominent notice on the web site so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. If at any time, you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement or believe that we have not adhered to this Privacy Statement, please feel free to email us at privacystatement@monster.com or call us at 1-800-MONSTER and speak to one of our representatives. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly answer your question or resolve your problem.

### Contact Information

Monster is the name under which Monster, Inc., a Delaware corporation, with its principal place of business at 5 Clock Tower Place, Maynard, MA 01754, and certain of its affiliated companies worldwide, do business. Monster, Inc. is the legal entity which determines the purposes and means of processing the information gathered at the Monster Sites. Thank you for using Monster and NursingLink. Update effective March 20, 2008.
